hey what's up guys my name is a Jonah
and welcome back to my stables last
series got a bit of a different set
today hope you guys like it today we're
gonna be talking all about what the this
keyword is in C++ did this that's kind
of hard to say so we have a keyword and
C++ called this which is only accessible
to us through a member function and the
function meaning a function that belongs
to a class so a method and inside a
method we can reference this and what
this is is a pointer to the current
object instance that the method belongs
to so of course in C++ we can write a
method a non-static method and in order
to call that method we need to first
instantiate an object and then call the
method so the method has to be called
with a valid object and this the this
keyword is a pointer to that object this
is actually very important to how
methods work in general I'm gonna be
doing an in-depth videos soon link that
will be help there about how how objects
and classes actually work kind of
internally today we're just gonna cover
what this means and how we can use it
and why it even exists so over here in
our code I'm going to make a class
called entity I'll give it a couple of
public fields here X&Y and then make me
a constructor which also takes in X&Y
now immediately you probably say that
what I want to do is assign these fields
these member variables with the values
of these parameters of course I could
use and initialize a list and just do
this and that will be totally fine that
would work however if I didn't want to
do that and I wanted to actually do it
in the body I would be faced with a
little bit of a problem because as you
can probably notice they have exactly
the same name so if I try and do x
equals x I'm actually just assigning
this X variable the parameter with its
own value which is just doing absolutely
nothing what I really want to do is
reference the X and y that belongs to
the class the actual class members and
that's what the disk a what actually
allows me to do so as I mentioned the
keyword is basically a pointer to the
current instance so to make this a
little bit more clear I'm just gonna
write it out here entity point so I'll
just call it a and I'll assign it to
this that is the type of this
technically if you hover your mouse over
you'll see that it's actually an NC
pointer constant so you could set it to
that if you want to however most people
don't most people just assign it to an
entity pointer because what Const means
on the right-hand side of this is that
when I'll allow
to reassign this to something else so we
couldn't write this equals null pointer
for example or attempt to actually
assign this to a reference here that is
non constant this sense we would
actually have to declare this as Const
like that if you want more details on
how Const works and what constantine's
in that context I made a video on that
which you can access by clicking the
card up there so anyway back to this see
what I did that if we now want to
actually assign X we can just do a arrow
X and just assign X or of course to make
this a little bit more simple we can
just do this arrow x equals x this is a
pointer of course so we need to
dereference it that's why we need to use
the arrow alternatively we could write
code like this but of course it looks a
lot cleaner with the arrow so most
people just do that and with Y I would
do the same so now we actually have a
way of assigning these two variables
which is very important because we we
couldn't have done it otherwise if we
were to write a function which returns
one of these variables for example it's
pretty common for us to marketers Const
because it's not going to be modifying
this class so in a Const function this
isn't actually equal to just an entity's
actually equal to a constant I see
because of course putting Const here
means that we're not allowed to modify
the class so this has to be Const so
that we can't get away with doing stuff
like this which would have been possible
if we didn't do that so in summary in a
Const function the actual type that
you'll get if you hover your mouse over
here you'll see is going to be a
constant entity point a Const or just a
Const entity pointer that's really the
part that we care about and then if you
access it inside a non-consumption is
just going to be an entity pointer
another useful case for this is if we
maybe wanted to call a function that was
outside of this entity class so it
wasn't a method but we wanted to call a
function outside this class from within
this class that took entity as a
parameter so as an example maybe we had
a print entity function and because of
the declaration water here I'm actually
going to have to declare this up here
and then define it over here so we have
a function that might do some cool
printing kind of stuff and we want to be
able to cooperate to entity from inside
this class so it may be like this I want
to pass in the current instance of this
entity class into this function how do I
do that that's where this comes in I can
just pass him this and that's
going to of course passing the current
instance with the X&Y that I've got set
here if I wanted to take this in as a
constant reference all I would have to
do here is actually just dereference it
and there we go
so of course would be referencing this
in the case of a non concert we'll just
get an entity reference back like so and
then a Const method we would get a Const
reference back like so because this is a
pointer to the current class we can also
do some pretty bizarre things such as
called delete this I've seen this code a
handful of times in very very
specialized cases my recommendation
would be of course to avoid doing this
because you're freeing memory from a
member function and if you decide to
ever access any member data after you
call delete this you're going to explode
because the memory had been freed so
don't don't don't typically write code
like this just make this is C++ there's
kind of a there's a place for pretty
much everything but but darn it maybe no
I don't anyway I hope you guys enjoyed
this episode I've actually upgraded the
audio a bit few of you guys for
complaining about echoing in rooms and
stuff so I'm using a different
microphone now hopefully it sounds
better let me know what you think in the
comments below if you want to support
this series and basically help episodes
come out quicker and be high-quality and
all that you can go over to patreon
Tacoma 4/2 Cherno you'll get some pretty
cool rewards so just getting episodes
early and being able to talk privately
in a cool kind of patreon on the discord
chat and all that fun stuff so
definitely check that out because it
does help support the series and it
helps me make way more videos I will see
you guys next time goodbye
[Music]